## **AJAY GHIMIRE**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### PERSONAL INFO

#### **ADDRESS**

7-9 Churchill Avenue, Strathfield, NSW 2135

#### **PHONE**

0404286785

#### **EMAIL**

ajayghimire1998@gmail.com

#### LINKEDIN

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ajayghimire/

#### **PORTFOLIO WEBSITE**

https://ajayghimire1998.github.io/ajay-ghimire/#/

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### **LANGUAGES**

- JavaScript
- Ruby
- Java (Actively Learning)
- HTML / CSS

### FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES

- React
- Redux
- Express.js
- Ruby on Rails

#### **DATABASES**

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- MongoDB

#### **TOOLS**

- Git Source Control
- AWS (Basic)
- VS Code and Eclipse
- Postman
- ChatGPT
- Microsoft Office
- Adobe After Effects

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Adaptability and Flexibility
- Collaboration

#### **PROFILE**

An aspiring junior developer with a solid 4-year foundation in software development from a bachelor's degree, combined with a software engineering bootcamp, and sustained self-directed study and professional development. Honed impressive problem-solving and creative thinking through continuous academic projects development. Driven by a desire and an unwavering commitment to leveraging technology for social good, seeking to pursue a fulfilling career in software development.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Full Stack Software Engineering Transform Academy Xi

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

#### COURSEWORK.

- Front-end Web Development
- Back-end Web Development
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Database Systems

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

- WITH LOVE FROM HOME
- GOALS TO SCORE
- MEMEBOOK
- CRYPTOMANIA
- PLAY MATES
- MOVIE FINDER

Bachelor of Information Technology and Systems (BITS) 
Major: Software Development

Victorian Institute of Technology

Jul 2018 - Jul 2021

Sydney

Sydney

#### **COURSEWORK**

- Programming Fundamentals.
- Web Development
- Database Management Systems
- Systems Analysis and Design
- Project Management
- Professionalism and Ethics

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECT**

COCINERO

#### RELEVENT EXPERIENCE

#### Web Developer Intern, Brand Easy Australia

Campsie

Dec 2022 - Present

- Collaborated with the development team to plan, develop, test, deploy, and maintain web applications.
- Participated in code reviews and documentation and contributed to the creation of technical documentation and user manuals.
- Worked with project managers to prioritize tasks and ensure timely delivery of projects.

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

- English (Fluent)
- Hindi (Proficient)
- Nepali (Native)

#### RELEVANT CERTIFICATIONS

- React + Redux 🗖
- Ruby 🗖
- Responsive Web Design

# ENROLLED & AWAITING CERTIFICATIONS

## AUSTRALIAN COMPUTER SOCIETY (ACS):

- Professional Environments (Currently Running)
- Professional Year Program (Completed)

#### OTHER EXPERIENCES

#### **Retail Assistant. Chemist Warehouse**

Dec 2022 - Present

- Developed exposure to Data Management by managing customer transactions and financial records using point-of-sale software.
- Sharpened problem-solving skills by collaborating with a team to resolve product availability issues and ensure the store was fully stocked.
- Improved customer service by assisting customers with their purchases, providing product information and recommendations.

#### Cook, Cho Cho San

22

Potts Point

Jan 2018 - Nov 2022

- Developed strong time management and multitasking skills by working in a fast-paced, high-pressure environment.
- Improved teamwork skills by collaborating with a team of chefs and servers to coordinate meal preparation and delivery,
- Demonstrated attention to detail and a commitment to quality by contributing to dishes preparation according to recipe and ensuring high quality presentation.

#### **INTERESTS AND HOBBIES**

- Playing video games
- Playing guitar
- Watching sci-fi and dystopian TV shows
- Writing LinkedIn posts
- Solving LeetCode problems

Brookvale